so all right we're going to do a quick
little video hopefully it'll be around
40 minutes about how to
organize your go repo so we we already
did so the last two videos we started
coding and go and you know we we we did
lots of different things we had uh we
had vs code running right and it was
really fun um so that's covered but now
how do you organize your files right and
and I wanted to avoid jumping into this
right away um because you know we wanted
to get get going with the code but now
that it comes time to kind of reorganize
particularly since you're trying to you
know organize your notes along with your
code it's a good time to start talking
about that and you may have noticed a
few changes already so I have changed my
readme file from uh MD to. AOK uh we
will talk about that today asid do
versus markdown which one you should use
and why um I'm not going to go and we
not going to show you how just maybe
what you want to do about that uh we're
going to talk about the go dood file
we're going to talk about the go. some
file and we're going to talk about
main.go we're going to talk about what
you would name your files we're going to
talk about how the files are interacting
with other files and how you should
organize your directory particularly
when you want to put other things in
there all right so let's get into it so
the first thing that you need to know is
that any any package uh a package is so
this goes in your notes a package is a
directory that has go files in it the
end the end right so if we were look at
where this is this actually main.go is
currently in a package called coding
from the get-go that is the name of the
package so if you were to reference
anything in here you would have to use
that and then you would put a dot after
that so we are not it's tough because
you know I want to teach you like for
loops and stuff before we get into how
to organize your modules but this um so
just know that a package is everything
in a current
directory folder whatever you want to
call it and um and and that's it okay so
uh everything that's in a a folder is
you know is a is a package and the name
of the package is the directory name all
right so the second thing to take away
from this is and I we could probably put
this in our notes here so uh I have my
notes Here get organized so let's just
make a thing so we could say a package
is anything uh is the current uh uh
directory name all right the second
thing is is that all go files all uh
go.go files in
directory are as if they were all in a
single file so that means that if you
split your program over several files
they're all the same as if you had a
really big big file the names don't
matter they just have to end with Dogo
there's one exception to that which
we're going to get into much much later
but that is um uh uh unit test
files uh unit test files uh have test.
go and uh but more on that
later okay there are we're also going to
talk there's a couple there's a couple
other special things you can do like
test data will be
ignored um we'll get into the modules
later but for right now you just want us
know how do I organize my code so um by
con by
convention you guys know what a
convention is a convention is things
something El people do that's not
required but it's generally a good idea
because everybody does it uh by
convention uh main.go
contains the entry point uh of the code
contains um Funk
main okay so by convention main.go
contains Funk Main and of course if you
have uh a funk main that means that the
package is also name uh also you know
package main we already talked about
that last time so so that means that
when you look at this you're like okay
this is a command right and so that's
another
takeaway uh uh all
packages uh are either commands or
libraries
okay so this is a very I'm picking these
words
carefully um so commands or libraries I
guess we could underscore these
Instead This is going to make it
metallic all right
so you either uh uh either your package
is either a command or a library okay we
we haven't gotten into what that means
um just know that a command is something
that turns into an executable and a
library is something that turns into a
binary library that can be imported by
uh and statically linked by another
program so that's the difference between
those two we'll get into how to make
your own libraries later but just so you
know that that's a thing um but that is
fundamental because that is going to get
us into one of the biggest conventions
so um and that is uh put uh General
package uh
code into PKG there's nothing that says
you have to do this um maybe put it on
your hoodie um yeah I don't know why let
me do that but so anyway put General
package code into
PKG so and say uh put uh packages put
let's see put command packages into CMD
all right so
Library
packages into PKG and put command
packages into CMD again this is not
required this is just a suggestion um by
that people will you you're just
paraphrasing stuff that you would read
elsewhere um so let's actually do that
all right so we've got to make
now um let's see I should probably put
this keep uh go. doc at the root
um okay uh which uh
um
identifies the top of the
module okay so a module what is a
module all right so a a
module is a collection of is is um
contains one or four more
packages all right you can have a single
package module um and there are a lot of
them that are that so like could say you
had a command right that is the thing
but usually they have more than that
okay so here's a kind of a question what
do you
think
um you know so let's let's make these
directories so make directory PKG
CMD and now what goes where you can
probably yes right well let's put main
into CMD all right so now main is in CMD
and uh we have the go. suum pile which
we'll talk about in a second and we have
the PKG pile now we don't have anything
in PKG right now and we probably won't
for a while but we can leave it there
and something to know about git is that
if you don't have a file in there uh
that directory will not appear so uh I'm
actually going to do a little trick here
I'm going to do PKG doke keep it's a
trick that people use to keep the
directory there even though when there's
nothing in it because that will will
show up in GitHub so if you're looking
through GitHub and you want to know
where things are or going to be you can
go in there and look at that so let's
just review all the changes we've made
so far um in our go.mod file it stays
the same it's the name of the GitHub
repo this is the module name and the
module name includes the full path from
the internet about where you get the
thing um I told you earlier that you can
actually change it to other things and
that's definitely true but you know
that's good for now um we actually have
this go. suum file which is new which
I'll talk about right now this go. suum
file contains the um check sums which
guarantee that the package that you have
a dependency on is loaded it tells you
which one it is and then it will always
make sure that you get the right one
this prevents the really the various
worms and things from like they taken
out npm before um from you know being
bad so anytime you have a dependency on
another tool you want that uh anytime
you think you might not have stuff there
we already covered this but go mod tidy
that will pull out to your dependencies
and your go. Su file will change so you
see it's now empty and that's because
there's no longer a dependency those
dependencies kind of crept in while we
were working on other things um you'll
notice that when I did that go mod tidy
U it also got rid of the extra lines in
my go mod file so let's put that in the
list uh
regularly uh use go mod tidy to remove
unused depths module dependencies you
know I I find this annoying because uh
you know go is so good at at that whole
thing about telling you when something's
not being used um and it won't even
compile if you you know you're importing
a package that's not being used and I
find that annoying because they don't do
that with
modules they should automatically go mod
tidy but they don't and the reason for
that is because of the same reason that
it gets annoying when they remove an
import line even though you're going to
add it right back immediately because
you just commented it out they they left
it out uh they don't have it
automatically removed because those
those check Su lines could be very very
important because they indicate what
exact version uh of a thing that you
have a dependency on and that's for
security reasons that's very important
and unless you explicitly say I want to
use a different version um assuming
you've checked to make it sure it's safe
and everything then they can't just get
rid of it because that would force you
to automatically upgrade it to latest
one you wouldn't be able to remember
what the last one was which by the way
is the reason that you should include
uh keep go.mod and go. Su uh in your uh
GitHub repos uh uh I should say Commit
This is actually really important um if
you don't do that you will get problems
um you will you strictly speaking if
your go mod is there and your go Su is
not it'll it'll create the gome file
from the go mod file as long as the go
mod file has the right versions listed
in it
um but you know go mod tidy removes both
of those when those are when those are
no longer needed um we're going to keep
coming back to this modules thing uh as
we learn more about go but that it's
probably good to give you this upfront
organization uh about the repo structure
um which so far is pretty easy to
understand right it's it's I think it's
easier than python to understand python
structures are you know the implied
underscore underscore and it and all
this different thing no just just
everything in the directory belongs to
the same package a module contains
multiple packages and the go. mod file
indicates that we have a package impack
I can remove that go out some file in
this case since we don't really need one
we have any dependencies if you want to
simplify things because it was empty you
can always delete the goome file and go
get it to go get the latest but if you
do that you're forcing yourself to get
the latest versions of everything and
that you might not want to do so that's
that's what we know about that um
okay and then we have a package
directory that doesn't have any packages
in it that's where our libraries are
going to go which we're going to make uh
either in the next lesson or the lesson
after that we're going to create a a
colors Library we're going to we're
going to make it so that we can use
terminal color and we're going to put
all those colors in a package that you
can reuse so that is coming um and but
we've already got our first command but
there's a problem some of you may have
already caught this when I go into the
CMD directory um
uh we so far the only thing you know
officially is go run because that's the
only thing we've covered is go run this
is how you run the program you know that
one we left off on but obviously it's
like you know I probably want to have
that to do something more there so let's
add some more stuff to our notes um okay
so uh make
sure um command uh packages uh have good
names all right so can you see a problem
here guys right so can you see a problem
what's the name of my what's the name of
my repo there right all right so let's
learn the First Command that you don't
know besides go run and that's like uh
builds we're going to do build um
binaries uh in same directory with go
build Okay so there's lots of options
for go build you can go look them up go
build DH if you want um uh or go help
build we're not going to go into all the
options just use the ones that we need
right now make sure you know how to use
a pager for this this is one of my
biggest pet pees would go is they
they're anti- text Rob Pike calls this
color juvenile um so I this is
impossible to read I I I really don't
like it but whatever um there are other
ways to read this by the way you can go
online and read it um and uh so anyway
so this tells you everything you can do
only thing you need to know right now is
this go build and when you do go build
it does something but what so you LS and
we see we have a binary brand new binary
here uh it'll tell you what type of
binary it is if you were to open it up
with you'll see that it's actually a
compiled binary just like C uh is
literally the same exact thing you get
from compiling in C or rust or any
compiled language for that matter um I
mean they're all compiled but you know
what I mean um explicitly compiled um
thank you for the fullex um so if we
look at it now we see that it's a
program and we have we can do the we can
run the program with CMD we can't just
run CMD because it's not in our path
which we've talked about in other videos
um you know my path is this they don't
have there's nothing you know there's
nothing in this particular path um and
you know that's all well and good
we can actually update our path to do
that but the problem is we don't want it
to be named CMD now there is another
thing you could do uh which I will tell
you but I you don't do it but I'll tell
you about it um so you could do
this uh build uh
binary with specific uh
name so you could use one of the- O
switches which is the same as C by the
way so you could do das o my CMD or
whatever hello how about
that right so we could do go go build
build- o hello this is very common see
people know this because when they're
using GCC or whatever they they know
about that show that takes makes a
binary name so it makes them very happy
because that's a cozy way to they're
used to that from C uh but now we have a
Hello program and you can definitely do
that right you can do that but if you
would rather move the program into your
now so so to in order to do hello like
this uh you know um so we do which hello
it it tells you where it is lab sample
it's finding it because we add it to the
path so in order to put one of these
programs in your path and you decide if
you want to do that but you might want
to if you want to put the program in
your path there's two ways to do that
one of them is to add you know the
current directory where you are um into
your past so that it's always in your
path every time you work on this project
um another way to do this though is to
use the go install command and what the
go install command does is um uh let's
see uh install into go
bin uh
uh in
path with go install
and I think you can actually do a dash
show with install but I've never done it
uh thanks this video will be here for
you in a bit well we're we're about done
with it here so so so to do the install
part we do we do what we do go install
now I don't want to to go install
why we didn't fix the other
problem why don't I do go install can I
I'm going to try something I've never
done this in my life I don't know if
this is even going to
work
um nope doesn't work okay so Das you- o
only works for build and does not work
for setting the name in the place you
want to put it so what the go install
program does is it takes it where it is
compiles a does a build and then takes a
binary and puts it into your go bin and
you can get your go bin with go
EnV uh go bin I think you think that
will do it yeah there we go so this
gives you your go bin um and you can set
that to wherever you want uh that's out
of the scope of this video to talk about
how to organize your your home directory
and stuff I do talk about that in
terminal velocity so please check that
out um and you know I I like to put
everything in loal so I put it in loal
bin and and in that directory you can
actually see uh a bunch of stuff
so uh go en V go bin
so this is all the stuff that's inside
of there and you can see there's a bunch
of stuff that I built in here uh if I
were to do a go install it would put CMD
in here but we don't want that right and
you can see the hello from the last time
we did this so I'm I'm missing some
things here let's get rid of this hello
program and let's get rid of this CMD
program and we have a main. go so let's
go ahead um
yeah let's see um see is
yes uh C is C is great but yeah go is a
great better first step in my opinion so
we're going to make a directory here you
know a package uh a command package
specifically called hello all right and
now we move our main uh into hello and
now when we go into hello we can uh you
know if we do a gold build obviously
it's going to make it the right name but
better than that we can actually do um
we can do go
install and now it will automatically
put like well what did it even do right
well now when we do Wich hello you'll
see that hello has been added um to
local bin so now I can actually add it
and we can run hello and it doesn't need
a do slash in front of it actually
that's
interesting that that's
interesting it's still using the the
other
one that's very
interesting it should have it should
have run this
one
what what's going on it's got to be my
path did it not override
what am I forgetting
guys this is interesting I think it
might be hashed
incorrectly
yeah this is this is why I do it live
this is fun stuff for you to find out on
your own Ben
[Music]
hello no okay so I that's
weird that is that is really
weird it's got to be hash
issue oh okay this this I'm glad this
happened okay this is a perfect
time to tell you why the witch command
can fail
you so the witch to man only tells you
which thing resolves in the order but it
doesn't tell you what hello is actually
doing for that you need to
type see
that you know how many times I've been
burned by that and I just got burned by
it
again when you want to know what is
running when you enter a command use
type that's the
takeaway okay this is a kind of command
if if I hadn't showed you that you would
never know You' be like what the hell
that's in the wrong path it's the right
program and everything this is because
it hasn't been hashed and you know what
this is not really a go thing but I
definitely putting it in the book
because um let me go back another one or
two
yeah all right so um
sometimes let's see use
type uh hello to
see uh what is being
run and um use uh
hash
dasr to
reset to latest
install this is this is a thing that you
know a few of you are going to run into
so by type by doing type hello there we
saw that it's not running that and I
have to tell it uh yeah so hash
dasr uh rehashes it and the reason this
happens is because some shells you have
to usually set it but some shells in
order to be fast they don't have to go
search the file system every time so
they remember the last location for
every session that you start and after
the first time you run it it has to go
find it and it takes a long time to run
it and after that it runs it immediately
because it's been cached and that's one
of the way the reasons it runs it so
quickly after the first time because it
it doesn't cat it into memory as if it's
going to rerun the same memory but it
caches the location in memory and so it
doesn't have to search through the file
system every
time I'm doing great so now when we do
Type Hello uh it it's now pointing to
the right one right so now when I run
hello it you'll get I'll give what
expected I knew it was a hashing related
problem but it I was still confused and
I was using which and so the takeaway
from that is don't use which use type
because it was saying it was which was
telling me the right thing but but type
was telling me a completely different
thing so and it was telling me how that
have been hash
so that's kind of in the woods in the
weeds as you say but so be it all right
so that means that now we've got you
know I can run hello anywhere and I get
the program as intended so while I'm in
here working on our program which we'll
continue to do after this we'll be in
here like typing away different things
and then every time I want to make an
install I just do go install and for
that kind of thing you can actually make
uh an alias uh or a command if you want
to in my case I made a command uh and
this is what I do um I just do go
install uh if there's a file there and
if there's not just go for it and so I
can just type and I regularly do
that um at this we have a little time in
today still so I'll tell you about a
couple of of the other uh well as we get
to them I'll tell you about them we
haven't done testing yet but when we do
I have a number of other like quick and
dirty aliases that I run all the time um
I want to say one last thing about this
though because um people regularly get
tripped up by this gotu and I need to
probably put this gotcha in uh my goang
gotas book um which you know this
hashing thing that should go in the
goang gotas book as well even though
it's not specifically go um a lot of
people would get tripped up by that um
so let's do this let's say
uh uh I wanted to talk a little bit
about the building so um make
sure let's see uh build let's see go
install go install uh let's see note
that go install
requires
um a i a full
path uh a a full uh
path uh to file
so like this go
install SL
CMD hello all right so this is not
intuitive and I'm telling you this
because you'll get burned by this so
let's say you don't want to have to keep
deep diving you can have multiple
windows open in different places you
know and I suggest that but sometimes
you just want it to all be from the top
level and um and you know just depends
on how you want to do your work
especially if you've got vs code it's a
totally different thing which before we
leave today we're going to do all of
this also from vs code um I haven't been
doing anything from vs code but I really
want everybody to understand that you
still need to do all these terminal
commands from BS code um there are tools
and extra extensions and plugins you can
get to do the building for you
automatically and all that but I suggest
that you continue to um you know build
your own command line interactions with
these kind of things so so right now
let's do that so to do go build from up
here um you know it's not going to work
it's like there's nothing to build go
install you already know my is is
like go install right so there's no go
files here so I have to tell it and so
this is this is where you're going to
screw up uh you're going to do CMD slash
right and then hello and you're like oh
why isn't that working that's not
working because for some reason and I to
tell you the truth I don't know the
reason go does not resolve the current
directory
relatively so go install CMD Holo is not
a thing and the only way to fix this is
to put dot slash in front that fixes it
which would seem to indicate to me that
go install is
hardcoded uh to not work on anything but
an explicit path it's not a fully
resolved path like with a slash in front
but it's a with DOT slash means that it
is a you know a resolvable path um and
it does not assume that CMD is in the
current directory that will do just fine
it's a tiny little glitch in go install
that drives me nuts but now you know
okay because you know I don't even know
the reason for that
um imagine at this point it's worth
mentioning if you know about other build
systems I'm not assuming you do because
I'm assuming you don't know anything
about coding at all but if you do know
about build systems it's probably worth
mentioning that this is the time at
which somebody generally will make a
build script uh or they'll write a make
file and we do have um 30 minutes left
in this video um so you not not quite no
so so I'm going to talk about things you
can do to speed up your build process um
and but I want to begin by saying that I
honestly do not think you need an extra
you know step to your building in go I
think that almost everything you can do
can be done just like we said so you
know go see especially once you have it
in your history then you can just go
back to it right um and you can run your
test this way and everything I don't
think you need more than that I think
you can use go as your build system and
you don't need an extra build system
it's very common to see phony make files
phony make files are my term for make
files that are mostly phony because they
have phony in them because they're using
make files for Shell scripts instead
when they could have just used a shell
script or in this case they could have
just avoided all of it and then just
known maybe even in the readme say to
build this do go install blah you're
done um one of the best things about go
is that there's no layer of build
process necessary on top of it you can
do that and many people do depending on
what kind of things they're building and
as our projects get more complex it kind
of Blends itself to it more but right
now you really don't need it um and you
know I I think you would it would be a
mistake but if you wanted to write a
shell script uh to do the build right uh
in this particular case and you or maybe
you only wanted to update one thing or
you only wanted to build one thing short
of learning make which is you know was
originally designed for C to you know
because C is a usually a bunch of little
teeny tiny dynamically linked libraries
getting built at the same time and then
you build one and then that triggers you
know a rebuild of a bunch of other
pieces and the whole idea is you don't
want to rebuild everything unless it has
to be done all this compiling as
probably we're saying is a byproduct of
go being and C being compiled language
explicitly compiled languages that's
what we'll say explicitly compiled that
means you do the compiling and um I'm
going to put that there uh go is an
explicitly uh compiled
um I'm going to is that a word I say
that
wrong explicitly compiled uh language an
explicitly compiled language uh like see
uh same with Java actually Java still
has B code but
whatever
so you know that's what we mean by
explicitly compiled and any language
that has explicit compilation like that
um when we did go run it was doing it
was compiling it for you and then it was
running it pretty fast huh faster than
python according to the specs so um you
know and when we do go test which we
haven't done yet but when we get there
go test does the same thing it it
compiles all your code it makes sure it
runs and then it it runs the test
against it which is so cool I cannot
wait to talk to you about this um in
fact I'm inclined to tell you about this
now because it kind of goes with what
we're doing and none of the other
languages I've ever taught beginners
have this so there's really no right
place to put it let's go ahead and do it
we've got 15 or 20 minutes left so let's
get organized even further let's
actually start our test driven
development which is a huge uh Pariah
it's like be careful how who you talk to
about this there's a lot of strong
opinions on this but let's actually
write a test right so um let's go back
to let's start by making our Command um
do a
thing
and well you know what we're going to be
having kind of trouble here
because uh do we well we're kind of
getting it hurt ourselves let's yeah
because we're going to be testing the
main package which is really weird
Nobody Does that they P they it's
generally it's generally not a thing to
write test Suites for commands I mean
for that kind of thing they would write
an entire container system and test the
command itself and entirely externally
from go but um so generally speaking you
want to test um functions and subes and
procedures which we haven't covered yet
but let's just let's just let's just
start really quickly uh because we're
going to come back to this later we're
going to be doing it a lot so if I
wanted to make it does this this is
related to the organization of the code
uh and where it goes that's why I think
we need to talk about it right now so
let's say that we wanted to make our
program so right now main is printing we
want to have it just print hello friend
we'll get rid of all these other things
for now um
and uh let's actually talk about
commenting really quick which we have
not covered um uh commenting can really
be covered anywhere so let's do that um
okay so comment uh comment a single line
with back slashback or SL
slash uh comment multiple lines uh with
this okay so that's how you do multiple
lines these are very very standard
comments uh in many many other languages
many of you will already be very
familiar with them uh I don't know why
that's doing that all right so let's
keep going we're we got we got plenty of
time left so let's say we wanted to take
all this stuff out right now there's a
couple of things you can do here um you
know I can do this in CMT and have it
like uh Do It
um and oops what happened to my B my CMT
command my CMT command is not happening
right now I need to go fix it anyway I
could do this right and you know some of
you will use visual mode for that I
don't I don't like that um sometimes I
use a filter that's what I do I have a
CMT filter um CMT where what happened to
my CMT oh oh no I renamed it prefix yeah
I did I forgot about that there we go
prefix so uh bing bing and then I do pre
and I'll comment and I I could probably
make another one that's called go
comment or something and and that'll do
that but you that's one way to do it um
another way that's really great I love
that they support this I use this all
the time and some people have macros and
stuff set up to do that uh you don't
need it you know it's pretty easy you
just add that there and add that here
and now these things are all commented
they're not being used so that's
comments comments uh comments we'll see
later are actually used for comments but
you know mostly comments are used to
turn code off
uh and and that's what we've just done
why did we do that um we did that
because we want to actually make this
code testable so you know whether you do
G run you no we don't want to do g run.
go I mean how do we really test this
right we could write a program that
tests the program but instead we're
going to make uh a test case a unit test
case File called mainor test. go and
again it does look a little weird to me
because we're testing the main package
which normally is not done um but let's
go ahead and go forward on this thank
you for the subscrib on that uh all
right so let's do this let's do main
test um and uh we have nothing here so
what goes in a test code right so the
first thing is it has to be the same
package so in this case it's Main and um
we're going to alter that a little bit
in just a second um so in this case it's
Main and there there is a we're not
doing it for main there in in another
world which we'll get to when we do
library packages you can actually do uh
mainor test so that you can have it
represent what you would write uh if you
had an external dependency on it but
that's getting a little bit ahead of
ourselves so let's let's write a test so
we're going to write a function we don't
know about functions but let's just
assume I'm going to show you how to do
this so let write test um we can write
test or we write example let's write
example uh and then we need to decide
what we're going to be testing so in our
case we're going to be testing the main
function itself which is very weird uh
but we're going to do that and then we
we make a comment as we already talked
about with the very special comment
called output and it has a colon after
it and then here we can say hello world
right did we put a does it have a DOT or
anything in it no it's hello print sorry
hello print all right and we probably
want a dot in there okay so this is the
structure of an example based unit test
and then we can do this we can say Okay
I want to run it so what are we going to
do how are we going to run it well we
need to just call it so we're going to
we can call Main like this and when we
run it it will do the thing now this
code is not something you can run
directly but you can directly run it
with go test when you run go test you'll
see that my test failed because it did
not give me hello friend with a period
it it shows me what it did get so this
is actually a really great way to just
the Habit to get into of testing your
code you can actually test your code AS
doing what you want even if it's the
main program as long as it has output
you can test it this way um and you know
you you could can decide that you're
overly zealously testing too many small
things that's up to you to decide how
granular to get with your test but for
right now we can do go test and we see
that we passed the test okay so there
there are many other ways to do unit
testing uh that are built into to go
that's really the takeaway from this um
and with regard to organization the
uncore test.of file that's what it is
it's there to run a unit test and when
this package is imported or exported or
any of those things or vendor the test
files are omitted they're not sent okay
and they're we're going to be dealing
with this a lot more as we go um but I
wanted to introduce you to that so you
can see uh what it means to to write a
test case um so we're actually making
sure that our program works without
installing it it did not affect the
install at all I can do to install
it I can do hello and you'll see that
the it's ad and it's now running the
right version um and we can go all the
way back up here and come back up
um and you can see these things are all
here so I think I think that's about it
we've introduced you to unit testing um
we've done you know so uh test let's see
create
uh uh same named uh file with
uh underscore test for unit tests okay
and then um uh and then uh add you need
to do the add the um output
comment um comment uh
followed followed by expected
output uh as
comment okay and then what did we do
then we did we ran go test T so uh run
go test to
check uh
unit example uh based uh unit test so um
the reason it's called an example is
because that actually doubles as
documentation um and I might be able to
show you that let me see if I can
demonstrate that to you even though it's
not a main part of what we're talking
about have a little time left um I think
you can do
this um let's see show documentation
for simple match case show it so a lot
of people don't know this but in go if
so a lot of this documentation is
available on the web um and I think it's
actually go do doc go do
doc uh go
documentation and this is not it we need
to go to the p packages here we go so uh
like let's go see for my bonsai package
so here's my bonsai
package and you can go read about it
here and what I'm trying to say is that
um all this great documentation shows up
but the really great thing is you see
all these examples we just put in our
unit tests they are now runnable
testable examples that show up in the
playground so when people are trying to
get acquainted with your package and
they want to learn how to use it um
because you've made it public then then
they can come in here and they can see
all this great stuff and so this this
topic is related to get organized um you
know you should start documenting
yourself from the very earliest part
don't don't overly document things
because you might end up refactoring it
and then you have to redo all the
documentation so and I am going to show
you a trick using Claude or chat GPT to
automatically write your comments for
you um not a lot of people know about
this but it's one of the most amazing
uses of AI I can think of nobody likes
writing comments for their code so it's
a really great way to get started and a
really great use of AI that doesn't uh
distract from from other things we are
going to do that but so don't don't get
too caught up in writing
documentation um yeah a generated PR
summaries there's a whole bunch of
things there that that quite frankly AI
is perfect for so don't waste a lot of
time on those those mundane tasks that
AI can really do for you um you know and
and and that's one of them um but
creating these examples I I haven't
successfully got uh any of the AIS to
write really great examples um ex yet
but that might be possible in the future
but I was trying to show you that those
examples become a part of your test
that's all I was trying to get at um and
that's why it says example because in
the absolute genius idea uh the go
designers they decided to not only
encourage unit testing by building it
into the language itself but also to or
into the tooling I should say but also
integrate testable runnable examples as
that double as unit tests I mean I don't
think I can overly State my admiration
uh for that in L genius idea on their
part and and I got to tell you I'm
really sad that the go Community as a
whole next time you meet somebody your
codes go ask them if they know about
example based tests straight up do you
know about example based tests and
they'll say no they don't know they
could be doing it professionally forever
they'll they'll know about about
testifier some stupid third party app or
package that's completely unnecessary
but they will not they discard the
opportunity to create really amazing
examples by writing example based tests
and it's an absolute tragedy it's a it's
a really really easy way to identify a
noob go
programmer because because they don't
know they've never truly learned it
they've just learned all these one
things that they just needed to get this
other thing done so um I cannot overly
uh it's a great thing for me to end this
video on because there's so many things
about code organization that go
completely ignored uh in the go
community and one of those things is
unnecessary complexity uh unnecessary
make files uh you know un un you know
unnecessary dependency on testifier
whatever your favorite external test
library is um and so don't don't do that
don't do that the the Beauty and the
Wonder and of our favorite goldilock
language here is that go is simple it's
designed to be simple it's designed to
be understandable from the get-go don't
break it by making your code repo so
convoluted that nobody can understand
what's happening in there I mean because
you're just completely against the idea
of go as being a comprehensible language
and you know having coded Pearl for more
than a decade and you know clean Pearl
for the most part except for my classes
pragma which manipulated the symbol
table um you know I I really enjoy the
fact that go is so simplistic and so
easy to to Gro and so easy to do it
singing so that's all I'm going to end
this video um it we're going to end at
47 minutes so take some time to organize
your go projects um and maybe learn
about the documentation a little bit we
will cover
documentation um it's which has it its
own syntax and before we leave um I do
want to end on the change that I made
from markdown to asid do I am not going
to dwell on it but I am going to tell
you why okay so this is going to get its
own video but I have found
um I have found writing books in asid do
to be better than markdown uh you can
find videos from me uh strongly
advocating for the use of of markdown
and markdown only based on its Universal
ity uh and you know support on GitHub uh
and simplicity in fact i' I've made
Metal languages uh to create my own
subdialects of markdown so that it would
be even easier for people to write notes
and
documentation and having been obsessed
with that for many many years uh and
writing documentation and stuff and
having been recommended to use asid do
from the late chrisn NOA who I'm so
happy she mentioned it to me as I
started publishing books
um I now have not only have I started to
adopt it uh for books but I have quite
honestly I have this is going to sound
crazy but I've banished uh markdown from
my life and let me tell you the main
reason for that um the main reason is
that asid do is designed for people
writing books and um and uh markdown is
not it's just not mark that as designed
for people who were making uh blogs and
simple things it can be adapted to write
books pandoc is a good example of that
um and it's amazing for that but it is
nowhere near as comprehensive as asid do
now a lot of people would say that that
is a negative that asid do is too
complicated for a beginner it has too
many bills and whistles and unnecessary
things and they're right it is it's if
for a beginner you probably do want to
still learn markdown but if you have any
inclinations to write
complex uh you know documentation or
notes and let me give you the criteria
for that do you want see this right here
this piece right here that's being
included okay that's being included from
another
source um so so that's what I'm saying
we will do 30 minutes on asid do we will
do a video about asid do it will not be
a part of the go coding series will be a
part of terminal velocity um because I
do believe writing documentation EI
either autodidactic or or terminal
velocity one of those two books uh that
will go in there so uh I'm also a fan of
of a of a practice which I given the
name Perpetual publishing which means
that you're constantly publishing uh
something in book form and it can be
digestable people can follow it and
quite recently I have discovered that um
asky do can be linked between completely
separate websites so I can actually
include asy do from a totally different
website where that ASI do lives and it
will automatically be included in my
build when I run the build and that that
single fact alone not to mention that
the ease of tables and the fact that you
can generate UBS and PDFs and everything
from asid do out of the out of the gate
uh makes asy the clear winner for me it
has full support for latch not just kex
which is just the math part so a lot of
people have suggested why are you not
just writing your books in latch l a Tex
and the reason is because I don't need
to I can do that at any time with asid
do it has full support for all of lch um
I realize that asid do is is kind of the
you know is kind of the the outside
person here but one of the reasons that
I switched it specifically related to
this is I was starting to write the book
uh in this repository along with the
code and the really great thing about
this is that this is I haven't included
this one yet I need to move it is that
you can actually have runnable code you
can have code that executes that can be
tested that is also a part of the book
so this module that we've been dealing
with this readme file is now going to
take the form of that and so the the
last thing I want to say here is that in
a directory like this quite frequently
you will see a doc directory all right
you'll see a doc directory like this and
that's where people put all of their
documentations um and they will they'll
put the you know they'll put it in there
A lot of times people don't know this
but you can actually Also
Serve um you know your your
documentation and stuff from this same
repository and I will be adding a build
script to this one to build my asy do
and I'm trying to decide whether I will
include that work as a part of um this
organizational stuff or not um either
way uh I'll do a video on that and that
video doesn't really belong in the in
the you know get coding from the get-go
but it it is related to taking notes and
taking notes is kind of a presupposition
on my part that you are going to take
healthy awesome amazing notes and quite
honestly I think the best way to do that
is with asid do um and the reason that I
um the reason that I think that's true
is because uh let me actually do one
right here for you so this is the
example that we had you see how I can
actually call out specific items in this
example here I can point to these items
these also are if you ever read a Riley
book they're already there that way okay
so if I wanted to change this and I
wanted to say I don't want that in there
I want to have include uh and this is a
good thing to end on and it is related
to documentation or to organization so I
I feel like it's okay let's so I want to
include what do I want to include here I
want to include command hello we'll tab
tab that out slash main.go main.go and
then put that in there and I don't I I I
have a call out here but the call out
doesn't say what it's being called out
for right but um I can actually um well
let's go add one so we add the main.go
there and we could say I could say uh
one I make some comment about that line
which you can do right so you can do so
you can actually learn how to publish
your own books at the same time as
you're taking notes and uh by doing that
now I can actually I can build this and
you we'll put a build script in there I
I feel like we need an entire hour about
how to do documentation so I'm going to
leave it there um and I am going to do a
full hour video uh about creating
documentation uh and I will I will put
it in coding for the get-go in this
particular uh Stream So that um it can
be done but but that video itself uh
should Stand Alone um so I'm going to
end this video for now this video has
been about how to organize uh your
directory and and and all of that and uh
we'll just let that go